# **Madalyn Breach**

Web Developer | Salt Lake City | madalynbreach@gmail.com

## **ABOUT ME**

I created a custom major to specialize in computer policy as well as programming because I believe it is important to design programs that are ethical, safe, and accessible to **mitigate risk** and **develop** *better*. One of my best strengths I bring to a workplace is my positive attitude. Us computer folk need some fun once in a while, it helps to have **upbeat** people around that can still get the work done well.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Westminster University, SLC (previously Westminster College)

Class of 2024

B.S. in Computer Science, Ethics and Policy | **GPA:3.38** (Honors College Certificate)

# **Madras High School**

3rd in Class | Honors Certificate | SkillsUSA Web Design 2nd in State | National History Day 1st in State

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Student Web Developer and Designer**

Office of Marketing and Communications, Westminster University, SLC June 2020-Present

- Communicates in a timely manner, experienced in a remote work setting.
- Prioritizes tasks each morning in an **Agile**-adjacent manner, collaborating with supervisors to review, test, and debug material before publishing.
- Experience with CMS migration that required a thorough inspection and restructuring of both front end design and back end support.
- Manages form building and implementation via Formstack.
- Underwent a full site redesign. Turned given graphics into code.
- Constantly researching and learning new ways to develop.

## **Assistant Computer Science Teacher**

Kearns High School (Title I), Kearns, UT Fall 2020-Spring 2022

- Assisted High School computer science teachers with little to no cs background with supplemental Exploring Computer Science curriculum tools, custom to the classroom and approachable to Title I students.

## **Teaching Assistant and Academic Tutor**

Westminster University Computer Science Department, SLC Fall 2020-Fall 2021

- Hosted weekly help sessions, assisted in class by tracking lab partners, managed breakout rooms, Q&A, and facilitated the zoom chat into live discussion.

# Caregiver with Adults Experiencing Disabilities

Opportunity Foundation Central Oregon

Summer 2018-On-Call Present

- Empowering 5 individuals by assisting them with every aspect of daily living including hygiene, transportation, eating, administering of medications, behavioral support and redirection, and communication.
- This job is the epitome of every soft skill in the book; I've never felt more challenged to be the best person I could be, every day, for the sake of my resident's quality of life. Because of the patience, care, and raw grit this job has required of me, I am fully confident in my ability to adapt, improve, and succeed at anything.

# **SKILLS**

# **Programming:**

HTML/CSS (Advanced) Javascript, React (Basic) Java (Proficient) Python (Basic) Agile

#### **Platforms:**

Slack, Asana, Adobe, OmniCampus, Sitefinity, Formstack, Spiceworks, Microsoft

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Personal Website:**

HTML/CSS/JS site that displays animated sky.

# **React Notes App:**

Post-it note board app built from a tutorial and debugged to fix spacing and element errors.

# Utah Pride Center Check-In Web App:

Django app intended for kids to use to check in to their zoom meetings.

# **COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT**

Harvard WeCode Conference (zoom)

YWAM Digital Media Coordinator and Sound Technician